## **Mariusz Boruc**

## mariuszbrc@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mariusz-boruc-a7402a74

# System Administrator/Solution Designer

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

I am a professional system administrator experienced in supporting companies from banking, energy, retail and broadcasting sectors. Graduated as an electronics engineer, I apply a systematic and logical approach to design IT solutions and troubleshoot IT issues. In the last 3 years I designed and implemented solutions which responded to security, migration and automation requirements. I am looking for opportunity to join an environment where I could contribute with my knowledge and develop in cloud solutions.

#### **EDUCATION**

- 2011 graduated with M. Sc. Eng. in Electronics and Computer Engineering at Warsaw University of Technology
- 2008 received B. Sc. in Electronics and Computer Engineering at Warsaw University of Technology

My education and professional occupation are recognized by:

- Australian Computer Society: System Administrator Ref. ID 1352230
- Australia Engineers: Electronics Engineer EA ID 5397844, App. ID 36945

#### **COURSES AND CERTIFICATES**

- AWS Certified Solutions Architect March 2018
- Puppet Fundamentals December 2015
- IBM Certified System Administrator (AIX 7.1) 2012
- IBM PowerVM Virtual I/O Server I: Configuring Virtual Devices 2012
- IBM FC storage for AIX on Power Systems 2012
- IBM PowerVM LPM on Power Systems 2012

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### BORUC LIMITED (CONTRACTING FOR IBM/CLS BANK) APR 2018 - NOV 2019 (UNITED KINGDOM)

I was Linux/Unix Administrator providing system administration services and designing Linux/automation/cloud solutions.

## Design tasks (from proof of concept to production deployment):

• Multi-factor authentication solution for SWIFT bank gateway systems • Backup-recovery solution for Linux servers based on REAR product • Migration of development environment to AWS (EC2 instances) • Automation solution for application scripts deployment using GIT and Puppet • Restricted shell implementation using native Linux tools • Veritas cluster design for scheduling system IBM IWS.

### System administration tasks:

● Installation and configuration of Veritas clusters to manage MQM, DB2 and WebSphere 
● Writing puppet modules for various tasks (application installations, configurations) 
● Upgrading operating systems – Linux. Performing disaster recovery tests 
● Installing and configuration of docker and docker swarm 
● Writing scripts mostly in Bash but also in Python 
● Providing BAU support tasks: setting SSH keys, configuring filesystems, managing users.

#### Documentation:

I prepared documentation at various stages of my projects: technical documentation and BAU procedures.

## BORUC LIMITED (CONTRACTING FOR SSE UK) JAN 2016 - APR 2018 (UNITED KINGDOM)

I was Unix/Cloud Administrator in the Cloud and Infrastructure Delivery Team. I was involved in preparing infrastructure solutions for the IT projects. I was very much involved in design of Smart Meter project where I collaborated with the Architect team.

#### Design tasks (from proof of concept to production deployment):

- Design multi-node Veritas cluster of physical Linux servers to host main application responsible UK Smart Meter project
- 2 Installation and configuration of hardware security modules (HSM vendor Thales) used for Smart Meter project
- Migration on-premises Linux servers (2) into Oracle cloud. Migration on-premises Linux VMs (20) into Azure cloud.
- Updating Linux bare metal recovery procedure to use new tool REAR
- Proof of concept of Ansible automation system for Linux VMs.

### System administration tasks:

- Provisioning virtual and physical Linux servers Managing RHEL Satellite and performing Linux upgrades
- Writing scripts in KSH, Bash and Perl. Writing Ansible playbooks which customized provisioned Linux VMs
  Supporting deployment of JBoss application.

#### Documentation:

I was following high-level design documentation and updating it with technical details of the actual solution. I was preparing BAU procedures and reviewing architect documentation (clustering Linux and cloud).

### KINGFISHER (B&Q) JUN 2015 - JAN 2016 (UNITED KINGDOM)

I was Unix SysAdmin in the Linux team.

#### Design tasks:

- Proof of concept of open source Puppet solution dedicated to support existing Linux infrastructure
- Script-based solution to monitor number of HTTP sessions established with www.diy.com

#### System administration tasks:

Provisioning virtual and physical Linux servers. Managing RHEL Satellite and performing Linux upgrades
 Supporting and configuring AIX servers and clusters in powerHA technology
 Writing scripts in KSH, Bash and Perl. Performing fail-over tests
 Supporting deployments of www.diy.com.
 Using Jenkins to perform standard deployment tasks.

#### Documentation:

I was preparing operational procedures for BAU tasks and provisioning guides, for example, how to create and manage ASM disks for Oracle database.

### IBM/POMEROY SEP 2013 - JUN 2015 (UNITED KINGDOM)

I was working as Unix System Administrator for a large international bank group (CLS Bank).

## Design tasks:

Proof of concept of Linux servers built on VMware, dedicated to run IBM AppScan application.

#### System administration tasks:

● Managing over 500 AIX servers: standalone and virtual (lpars) ● Configuring IBM NIM and IBM CSM tools. I was working with HSM consoles and VIO servers ● Configuring TSM backups clients. Performing global disaster-recovery failover tests (between UK and Belgium) ● Managing users, setting SSH keys and standby calls (24/7). Dispatching tasks between other members of my team

## Documentation:

I documented the Linux environment solution. These were first Linux servers deployed on the account and they were still providing services when I re-joined IBM/CLS in 2018.

#### MERITUMBANK DEC 2012 – AUG 2013 (POLAND)

I was UNIX/Linux and hardware administrator providing system administration tasks. I was also given a big project to design and implement global backup solution based on IBM TSM.

### Design tasks (from proof of concept to production):

TSM backups solution. The backup solution was dedicated to cover all servers in the bank, including AIX, Linux and Windows. The design also included SAN network configuration and storage configuration (tape library).

#### System administration tasks:

● Provisioning AIX and Linux servers (most of them were virtual)
 ● Migrating AIX servers from version 5.1 to 6.1.
 Upgrading AIX/Linux operating systems and firmware (FC switches)
 ● Performing disaster-recovery tests. Part of on-call rota (24/7)
 ● Administering WebSphere, deploying application packages
 ● Administering SAN network and storage devices (DS4800, V7000, V3700)
 ● Scripting in Bash. Tuning AIX server to improve performance of Oracle database.

#### Documentation:

I documented backup solution with respect to server and client setup. I also wrote maintenance procedures to manage the tape pools and backup policies. This documentation had to be compliant with federal requirements related to financial backup retention policies.

### **IBM Jan 2012 – DEC 2012 (POLAND)**

I was Unix/Linux administrator. Apart from system administration I designed AIX cluster solution for the client.

#### Design tasks:

Cluster solution for AIX servers using HACMP/powerHA. The solution was to provide high-availability for SAP systems running on AIX. Before going live, the solution was presented to my IBM menthor and then to the client. The resilience of the proof of concept was tested beforehand it went into production.

#### System administration tasks:

● Provisioning AIX virtual servers on pSeries and Linux servers on zSeries 
● Managing AIX and Linux (SUSE, RedHat).

Installation and upgrade of SUSE servers on zSeries mainframe servers 
● Configuring NIM, SDDPCM, HMC consoles and VIO servers 
● Server tuning for Oracle and DB2 databases. OS reconfiguration for SAP 
● Scripting in ksh and bash. BAU activities and standby calls (24/7) 
● Supporting deployments for major banking clients in Europe including Deutsche Bank and Bre Bank.

## COMPAREX OCT 2010 - APR 2011 (POLAND)

I was System Engineer providing on-site support for a large telecommunication customer in Poland - Play.

### Design tasks:

Planned and implement physical relocation of EMC storage array along with IBM pSeries servers.

This involved hands-on managing of physical relocation of the hardware.

#### System administration tasks:

● AIX and Linux administration. Maintenance of EMC storage and FC Brocade switches ● Setting SAN zones and network configuration (VLans). Nagios and NetBackup clients' configuration ● Server tuning for Oracle database. HACMP 5.3 clusters build and design ● Taking part in multi-vendor application deployments (billing system)

## Documentation:

Writing general technical documentation. Documenting network infrastructure of relocated hardware in the new data centre.

## POLISH TELEVISION SEP 2008 - SEP 2010 (POLAND)

In my first job, I was working as an IT and technical engineer.

#### My main duties included:

Managing AVID production system (Windows 2003/2008) specific for broadcast television
 Monitoring and configuring local storage arrays with capacity up to 30TB
 Physical server installation and configuration
 Testing new applications dedicated to live digital emission
 I was working during live TV shows as audio-video operator.